Mobile: (+44) 7455-193-240 **Curriculum Vitae**

Profile: Agile Solutions architect, trainer and coach with extensive experience delivering software to challenging deadlines.

I'm passionate about technology and have an in-depth knowledge of software architecture and agile practices, including digital architecture, Continuous Delivery, and DevOps tool chains.

This experience has been gained in diverse sectors including e-commerce, FinTech, financial services, private investments & equities, telecoms and consultancy.

Education

Diploma in Humanities Microsoft Certified Professional

Publications

The Flyweight pattern, Visual Systems Journal, pp. 20-21, July 2009 available at: https://tinyurl.com/vsi-theflyweightpattern

My blog available at www.garfieldmoore.co.uk

Open source projects: https://github.com/garfieldmoore

Professional memberships

British Computer Society (MBCS) IEEE Computer Society

Security Vetting

Baseline Personnel Security Standard (BPSS)

Professional experience

November 2018 – August 2019 Solutions Architect, boilerjuice.com

Skills: Software Architecture, AWS, Micro-Services, event driven architectures, Data

Lakes, DevOps, Rest API design, Terraform, Cloud Formation

I joined BoilerJuice on a 3 month assignment to define the technology roadmap for their current monolithic system.

I documented the current architecture, and proposed a new architectural direction that would meet future aspirations to support innovative products and overseas expansion.

I defined the solutions for the following initiatives;

- Defined a roadmap to evolve the monolithic website to an event driven & service based architecture
- Reduced infrastructure costs by 30% while managing all aspects of DevOps.
- Designed Monitoring & Logging platform and managed the implementation.
- Designed and built a Data Platform.
- Led improvements in all areas of the platform including security and privacy
- Introduced and defined automated build & deployments, and infrastructure as code
- Promoted improvements to development practices and tooling, including test driven development.

This work involved educating the product and engineering teams using workshops, demos & coaching as well as negotiating various improvements with senior stakeholders.

Mobile: (+44) 7455-193-240

March 2018 - October 2018 Principal Architect, Valtech

Skills: Software Architecture, enterprise architecture, COTS, Road-maps, Azure, AWS, Serverless architectures, architecture styles and patterns, security principles

Client: Toyota Financial Services

- Led feasibility study for FinTech platform
- Documented the current technology landscape and synergies between several European markets
- Created a proposal and architecture road-map for the future platform

• Client: Ofgem

- Designed solution to take PII data from energy suppliers, securely store and integrate with price comparison websites.
- Worked with stakeholders to identify appropriate quality attributes.

November 2016 - November 2017 Senior Solutions Architect, Sopra Steria

Skills: Software Architecture, Road-maps, COTS selection, Agile governance, DevOps, AWS, Angular, Node, .Net Core, enterprise architecture

- Designed and led Digital capability assessments for our clients
- Led teams developing proof of concepts for departments Bi-Modal digital offering
- Defined solutions architecture and led development teams in various consultancy projects
- Advised on delivery models and governance for offshore agile delivery
- Delivered agile workshops for our customers and our offshore teams

June 2015 – September 2016 Technical Lead / Agile Coach, Reed Business Information

Skills: Agile coaching, software architecture, technical leadership, TDD, agile stories, Puppet, Vagrant, AWS, HPCC, ASP. Net MVC, Angular, mocha, chai

- Turned around high priority failing project within 3 months of taking over technical leadership.
- Managed sensitive team dynamics.
- Coached remote teams in Agile practices including creating and managing requirements, XP development, release management and automation practice's.
- Influenced the solution architecture of big data and LoB applications.

July 2012 – June 2015, Technical Lead / Solutions Architect, 1e.com

Skills: Lean Start-up, Kanban, REST, Micro-Services, Continuous Delivery, Azure, MongoDB, Windows and network infrastructure, Asp.Net MVC 5, Vagrant, Angular JS, Bootstrap, Python, php

- Led remote distributed teams introducing improvements across requirements, development, & QA resulting in more predictable estimates and faster delivery time.
- Introduced Lean Start-up methods to enterprise organizations for new product development. Influenced senior stakeholders to adopt these methods, resulting in joint development partnerships with Fortune 500 companies.
- Responsible for architecture while leading the design of a complex cross platform client-side virtualisation solution.
- Evangelised modern working practices including the use of chef, vagrant, TDD, & automation frameworks.

July 2011 – April 2012, Director of Engineering, Broadway Financial Technology

Skills: Lean start-up, Continuous Delivery, Project management, PCI & DPA compliance, software architecture, Team City, Git, Agile development & testing

- Built technical team and agile development capability for a financial technology (FinTech) start-up.
- Defined architecture, infrastructure, chose development tools and development methods in line with business
 goals.
- Set strategy for development, automated test and continuous delivery and led team during implementation.
- Built relationships with third party suppliers, including Rackspace, Call Credit, RBS & Yodlee.

Mobile: (+44) 7455-193-240

September 2009 - July 2011, Tech Lead, thetrainline.com

Skills: C# 3.5, Domain Driven Design, Design patterns, XP, Lean, Continuous Integration, Subversion, Git, Cruise-Control, Nant, NServiceBus

- Introduced agile methods leading the fulfillment development team to deliver more predictably and faster
 - Our working practices became the standard for all teams
- Improved cross team processes to enable these improvements to spread across multiple teams.
- Overcome project hurdles & team knowledge gaps by developing relationships with other teams.
- Developed frameworks to increase developer productivity and led project architecture
- Our working practices became the standard for all teams

Sept 2008 – July 2009, Software Development Consultant, Automatic Data Processing

Skills: C#, ASP.Net, JavaScript, CSS, XHTML, XP, AQ Time, design patterns, MSMQ, Windows debugging tools, SaaS, IIS, SQL Server 2008, VB6, CruiseControl.Net

- ADP UK's core payroll application hosts hundreds of clients and accounts for millions of pounds worth of
 payroll transactions per month. I reported to the software development manager and was responsible for
 resolving client issues in the production environment.
- Delivered and advised on scalability improvements to multi-tenancy payroll product. This led to cost savings in infrastructure and application support as well as being able to support larger clients.
- Reduced cost of support by developing tools to automate frequent tasks.

March 2008 – September 2008, Senior Software Developer, CDC Software

Skills: Agile Methods, C# 3.5, TDD, WCF, SaaS

- Worked as part of team implementing .net win-forms customer complaints & feedback product. I became an integral part of the team, advising on object oriented design, enterprise design patterns and guided developers in the adoption of test driven design.
- Introduced pair programming as a way to increase developer productivity to meet aggressive project deadlines.

October 2007 - March 2008, Agile Consultant/Architect, Zurich International

Skills: XP, RUP, Scrum, C#, ASP.Net, WCF, analysis patterns, Domain Driven Design

- Coached team in the adoption of Scrum, TDD.
- Initiated a process improvement exercise that resulted in more productive use of resources.
- Worked alongside enterprise architect to specify SOA architecture.

March 2007 – August 2007 Software Architect, Crimson Systems

Skills: Agile Methods, RUP, ASP.Net, Test Driven Development, Design Patterns

- · Led team of developers in the design and implementation of Distributed Application
- Introduced agile methods for RUP and mentored programmers in there use.
- Facilitated workshops and gave presentations on Object Oriented best practice.

Oct 2006 – Jan 2007 Lead Agile Developer, Scottish Widows Investments

Skills: C#, ASP.Net, Agile Methods, Scrum, Design Patterns, Domain Driven Design, Web Services

- Technical lead during the design and implementation of front office enterprise software
- Delivered business benefit ahead of schedule by introducing agile methods and scrum.

March 2006 – October 2006 Application Architect, Coller Capital Ltd

Skills: C#, ASP.Net, VS 2005, SQL Server 2005, Web Services, ASP.Net, Design Patterns, XML, XSLT, Object Oriented Analysis & Design Methods

- Corrected defects in private equity investment software 70% faster than expected.
- Designed and implemented a system to integrate data from an external supplier. This became the reference design and demonstrated how agile methods can deliver ahead of schedule.
- Delivered a dynamic help system with a 50% reduction in expected effort and demonstrated how agile methods can be used to overcome unknown factors in system design.

Mobile: (+44) 7455-193-240

March 2004 - December 2005 Application Architect, T-Mobile UK

Skills: VB6, C#, Java, MSMQ, Oracle, Solaris/Unix, SQL Server, Design Patterns, Win32 API, VB Script, PERL, Agile Development, OO Analysis Methods

- Ensured stakeholder project support by redesigning software architecture to meet quality requirements.
- Designed a road-map for the product suite and led a team of developers during the design and implementation of a Fault-Tolerant Real-Time architecture. This architecture supported the integration of components in disparate technologies, including Java, C#, VB6, VBScript, PERL, XML, MSSQL Server and Oracle.
- Negotiated conflicting customer requirements to mutual benefit.

July 2003 - October 2003 Senior Developer, Optimax

Skills: C#, VB.Net, Web Services, XML, XSLT, Object Oriented Analysis & Design Methods

• Delivered a productivity tool for marketing team to challenging deadlines. This became the reference architecture for future projects.

November 2001 - February 2003 Senior Developer, CGS Solutions Ltd

Skills: VB.Net, Access 2000, XML, XSLT

• Database design and prototyping for an e-commerce site.

June 2001 - November 2001 Senior Developer, Misys PLC

Skills: VB6, SQL Server, XML, XSLT, CSS, HTML, UML, Design Patterns

- Worked as part of a team designing a point of sale system for use by Independent Financial Advisers.
- Researched & advised on user interface design for non-expert users.
- Influenced user interface design by using knowledge of domain.

August 2000 - April 2001 Application Architect, Siemens Business Services

Skills: VB6, C++, C#, VB.Net, Java, UML, Design Patterns, WIN32 API

- Reduced development of application suite by 66% by designing & developing an application framework.
- Coordinated a small development team within Prince 2 environment.

March 2000 - August 2000 Senior Developer, Pearl Assurance

Skills: VB6, XML, XSL, MSMQ, Oracle, SQL Server, UML, Design Patterns, WIN32 API

- Worked as part of a team developing a point of sale system.
- Reduced development time by 50% while designing legacy adapters.
- Designed MSMQ components to enable applications to communicate with each other

February 2000 - March 2000 Software Developer, Tibbett & Britten

Skills: VB6, SQL Server 7, VBA

- Integrated distribution tracking software with Microsoft Office applications.
- Advised on user interface and database design.

May 1998 - November 1999 Senior Developer, ACNielsen (UK)

Skills: VB6, Unix Scripting, Design Patterns, WIN32 API

- Led development of a suite of Business Intelligence software.
- Improved the communities' perception of the project by improving the user experience and resilience of the software and working closely with stakeholders to ensure business requirements were met.

Mobile: (+44) 7455-193-240

December 1996 - October 1997 Senior Developer, ASR Computers Ltd

Skills: VB5, FoxPro 2.6, Visual FoxPro, WIN32 API

• Tripled configuration consultant's productivity by developing tools to automate configuration at client sites.

March 1996 - October 1996 Lead Developer, Howard Fennel Ltd

Skills: VB4, Design Patterns, WIN32 API, ODBC, Object Oriented Analysis & Design Methods

- Quickly brought product to market in consultation with domain experts.
- Involved in presales process, demonstrations and product support.

January 1995 - March 1996 IT Consultant, LIS Ltd

Skills: VB3, MS Access

• Increased accuracy and competitiveness of tenders by implementing COTS solutions for estimating mechanical engineering works.

January 1994 - December 1994 Lead Developer, Synergy Software

Skills: VB3, C++, object oriented analysis

- Increased customer satisfaction by improving reliability and resilience of data service and delivery systems.
- Collaborated with market experts to develop innovative financial instruments.

1991 - 1993 Developer, Omnidata International

Skills: Z80 Assembler

• Integrated data collection and electronic instruments using Z80 assembler.